Alex Savin

samehome@yandex.ru, skype: sameskyperman, +7-921-3882934

Summary

I had started as desk helper at Internet-cafe, spoke with clients, had worked at nights, was studying. After that, I was involved to the hosting industry, where learned more about system administration. Wrote work with name "Testing graphical applications" as finish step of my grade. Further, I joined small team of Java developers and configurators at company that developed SaaS solution for Vodokanal (water supply system on Saint Petersburg). There I grew up by steps: system engineer, head engineer/developer (Java), CTO. In 2011 Yandex, the largest Russian search engine, hunted me. There I work for nowadays as developer with responsibility for various parts of the vertical search services, such as Yandex.Auto, Yandex.Rabota, Yandex.Realty more or less on Java, Scala/Akka, C++ code base.

Administrator, tester, developer, and (my opinion) a little bit manager - nice set.

Experience

Developer at Yandex

April 2011 - Present (3 years 3 months) Developing Java services

CTO at Favor-IT

April 2008 - April 2011 (3 years 1 month) Developing, managing and deploying software for water analysis

System Engineer at Favor-IT

March 2006 - March 2008 (2 years 1 month) Managing server farm for the SaaS solution (water analisys)

System Engineer at BizHost

July 2005 - December 2005 (6 months) Web hosting, mail hosting

Administrator at QuoVadis Internet Cafe

June 2003 - June 2005 (2 years 1 month) One of the first Internet cafe at Saint Petersburg

Certifications

Machine Learning

Coursera December 2013

Projects

Yandex.Rabota

April 2011 to Present

Russia's largest vertical job search engine aggregator.

Yandex.Auto

August 2013 to Present

Car ad offers aggregator

Yandex.Realty

January 2014 to Present

Realty offers aggregator

Languages

Russian (native), English (Intermediate level)

Skills & Expertise

Hosting Services, SaaS, Java, Linux System Administration, Java Enterprise Edition, SQL, PostgreSQL, Search, Maven, Hadoop, Bash, Scala, Akka

Education

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Master of Science, Computer Science, 2005 - 2006

Saint Petersburg State Polytechnical University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science, 1999 - 2004

Interests

Electronic music, Classic movies